Hello everybody, Adam Lusk here and
today we're going to be talking about
static and distilled embedding models.
Essentially, a few older techniques of
using static based embeddings, which
we'll get into in a bit, have resurfaced
with some modern updates to create
embedding models that are both 400 times
faster without losing a whole lot of
quality. If you know anything about me,
I put a lot of time into optimizing the
retrieval step of a retrieval augmented
generation pipeline, which heavily
relies on the embedding model. As a
quick refresher, embedding models play a
huge part in the machine learning
ecosystem, allowing us to do things like
textual similarities, semantic search,
paraphrase mining. It's even the kind of
models that are behind actually
highlighting the piece of text in an
article that's best to answer a question
that you input if you Google it. They're
pretty much trained through large
corpuses of text and content to be able
to take in some form of unstructured
data. Generally in our context, we're
going to be working with something like
text, running it through a machine
learningbased model, and then outputting
a semantically rich representation in
numbers of that data object. What that
means is we're essentially converting
something like text and natural language
into numbers. And those numbers are
going to capture the actual semantic
richness and meaning of the text, which
allows us to do things like
mathematically compare how similar
things are because we're now able to
represent them as numbers. These kinds
of models predate the large language
model as we know it and are some of the
original forms of language modeling that
was actually very successful. We've seen
advances with things like BERT or
birectional encoder representations from
transformers coming out of Google pretty
much revolutionizing this field and some
of the most downloaded models are
embedding or encoder models like all
many LML6V2 here that boasts an
impressive almost 83 million downloads a
month. If you want to learn more of the
specifics of exactly how things like
BERT models and transformer models that
do these sentence encoding actually
works, I implore you to check out my
other video, which I'll have linked
right above here. But one of the core
issues that's been identified with
modern-day embedding models like the
lovely alin here, is that there's still
a roughly large amount of parameters.
While relatively trivial in comparison
to some of the 70 and 100 billion plus
parameter models that we see with large
language models, they can still reach
pretty decent parameter sizings, which
in turn means that you need some pretty
decent hardware to be able to run large
scale tasks on these kind of things. So
today we're going to be looking at a few
different efficiency gains that we can
get using some older techniques with a
modern twist with the static embedding
models and also showing how you can use
an existing model and distill it down
into a static embedding model itself to
push the performance and efficiency of
embedding models. But before we do that,
a quick word from the sponsor of today's
video, Brilliant. Brilliant helps you
get smarter every day with thousands of
interactive lessons in math, science,
programming, data analysis, and
artificial intelligence. A lot of people
ask me how I stay on top of the
everchanging field of AI. And it's not
by doing everything all at once, but
rather learning a little bit every
single day and applying what I know.
With Brilliant, you can start to build
those daily habits of learning something
and applying something new every day.
With just a few minutes, you can turn
your mindless scrolling into actual
productive time, jumping into useful and
applicable topics for both your personal
and professional life. One of the
courses that I think is particularly
beneficial is the programming with
Python course. It's something I use
every single day, and Brilliant's newly
updated programming courses are a great
way to build a foundation in coding. Not
only can you do things like get familiar
with Python and start building programs
from day one, but the more important
thing is that Brilliant's course here
helps you develop an intuition for
computer logic. So, not only will you
learn strong fundamentals about
programming, but also a little bit of
how to get yourself in the mindset of a
programmer. To try everything Brilliant
has to offer for free for a full 30
days, visit
brilliant.org/adamlusk or scan the QR
code on screen or you can click on the
link in the description. You'll also get
20% off an annual premium subscription.
Thank you to Brilliant for the sponsor.
Now, back to the video. So, the first
thing that we're going to go over is
what are static embeddings? And to do
this, we're going to look at one of the
earliest, most popular static embedding
models, Word Tube Vec, which came out in
September of 2013, which in AI years
seems ages ago, and is a cool model that
came once again out of Google. And so
what Google showed is two novel model
architectures for computing continuous
vector representations of words from
very large data sets or essentially
being able to take large corpuses of
text and training a model to be able to
effectively represent the text as
numbers. And so while this idea of
encoding and representation is shared
across both static and dynamic
contextual or transformer-based
embeddings, what the actual core
difference between static and the more
popular these days transformer-based
embeddings are is that static embeddings
are going to be a predefined per token
level embedding. Jumping down to a
couple of diagrams here to show exactly
what we mean here is that the advantage
that the transformer-based embedding
model has is that it's able to use of
course the attention mechanism to be
able to give more contextual meaning to
specific words. So every time you
actually encode a sentence, each one of
the words in the sentence is going to be
considered as it relates and correlates
to every other word in a in the entire
sentence. This can highly change the
actual definition and meaning of the
word. Looking at something like I have
no interest in hearing about the rising
interest rate of the bank, we can see
that interest here means something more
like desire or intrigue. Whereas the
second interest means more monetary and
physical. Now, the beauty of the
transformer and attention mechanism
within some of the more modern
approaches here is that we can very
granularly identify the different
meanings of this word interest as it
relates to everything else in the
sentence. So, it's very contextual and
dynamic. Static on the other hand is
going to have one assigned embedding for
every single individual word or subword
token level. So rather than calculating
the entirety of the representation of
the sentence every single time, we're
essentially going to be creating a
lookup table where each word or subword
is going to have a corresponding vector
that's learned through the mass scale
machine learning on a large corpus of
text. How does this happen? Well, we can
look at the two specific ideas that the
Google paper introduced. Continuous bag
of words or from now on I'll just say
SIBO and skip Graham. These are
essentially going to be training
objectives where the model during its
training is going to be trying to do a
specific task and through this task and
through many many thousands and millions
if not hundreds of millions of examples
is going to learn how the actual human
language works to be able to do this
representation accurately. So for
something like skipgram gram what we're
doing is going to be predicting the
surrounding words in a context window
given a center word. So for the example
of a context window of three and the
sentence, the quick brown fox jumps over
the lazy dog. If we look at this middle
example here and have the word fox, the
predicted words that we would want are
the quick brown and jumps over the or
for something like the at the start, we
would want to predict quick brown fox.
And then continuous bag of words is a
little bit of the inverse of skipgram
gram where given the surrounding words
we are going to predict the center word.
So given the quick brown jumps overthe',
we would want to predict fox. Now if
you're unfamiliar with how kind of you
know machine learning and language
models are trained like this, what's
going to go on is many thousands and
millions of these examples are going to
be shown to the model. The model is
going to be trying to predict either
these outside words if using a skipgram
model or the inner target word given the
continuous bag of words approach. And
what's going to happen is that the
output from the model which might be
something like quick brown fox in
comparison to the when this is ran
through are going to be compared to the
actual expectation in the ground truth.
And then given the accuracy of the model
to actually be able to do that
prediction, what we're going to do is
update all of the inner numbers or the
weights and biases within the model to
maximize that accuracy. So over time,
the model will become better at actually
doing this specific task. And if we look
at something like languages here, that
means that it's going to build a better
internal understanding of language or be
able to model language. Thus, using
these kind of fill-in-the-blank or
predict around approaches to training
language-based models can help actually
instill and generalize over the many
millions of examples that tend to be
shown to actually do have some sort of
inherent understanding of how language
works pretty much because you're able to
understand what words go where. These
two approaches are not the only ones
that have been used to train static
embedding models. We've also seen the
idea of word co-occurrences and
frequency pop up. Things like the glove
model or global vectors for word
representation coming out of Stanford
use this co-occurrence matrix in an
interesting way which essentially posits
that words tend to be grouped together
and in training with something that
follows a occurrence or frequency based
approach we can capture that
distribution of semantics of language
based on kind of this specific
principle. Now before we actually show
some of these static embedding models in
action, I do want to talk very quickly
about the act of tokenization.
Tokenization plays a very big part in
this because essentially it's going to
create what is known as the vocabulary
for these models or the entire range of
different words or parts of words or
combinations of characters that are
going to be learned and understood over
this training process. It's likely that
you're familiar with tokenization
because of how it applies to language
models. We're taking raw text.
Essentially, it's going to be split into
all of these individual components. So,
something like many is going to be one
token, but then this space and words is
going to be another token, and it's
going to take an entire sequence here
and essentially chop it up into
individual pieces. These of course do
not usually take the form of just
playing characters like this. Rather
they become the numbers and then these
numbers correspond back to the specific
text. So that in the life cycle of
actually interacting with something like
a language model if you input a prompt
maybe it's something like this it gets
converted to numbers. Those numbers are
then input into the LLM which is then
able to be calculated and do the next
token predictions. And then those next
predicted tokens from the language model
are then mapped back to the text to give
us our plain English or any language for
that matter output. Now, this plays a
part because essentially every single
one of those tokens is going to have a
corresponding embedding that is learned
through the training process of these
static embedding models because as
mentioned, we're essentially going to be
creating a learned lookup table where
then as we pop in some sequence of text,
each of the individual words or however
it's tokenized are going to be split up
and then all of the premputed embeddings
are going to be mapped back to those
tokens. For the sake of example, we
generally look at full words split up as
individual tokens. But in general, as we
just saw, it can be a little bit more
complicated than that. However, creating
a fixed vocabulary using something like
tokenization is taking first your first
corpus of text and converting it all and
mapping all of those words using a
tokenizer into the actual numbers. We
then usually identify all of the unique
word tokens, apply some sort of
frequency threshold to exclude very rare
words, and then often we set some form
of maximum vocabulary size. Usually this
is around 32,000 or upwards depending on
how crazy you want to get. And then
different special tokens such as
representing out of vocabulary words or
other maybe unique Unicode characters
are going to be input in. That was a
very very simplified explanation. So I
definitely recommend and we'll be
linking in the description below to
watch the greatest to ever do it. Andre
Carpathy here. Build the GPT tokenizer
from scratch. This will certainly help
you understand the wacky wild world of
tokenization. But when we're actually
inputting a sentence like we love NLP
back into a static embedding model, it's
going to undergo the same tokenization
and then essentially all of the words
are going to be mapped back to the
vocabulary of this model. So within our
vocabulary, we are going to have a
corresponding learn vector
representation of each one of these
words. Now having the representation of
each word is kind of useful but
generally you want to encode sequences
of words which is where we actually
start looking into different pooling
mechanisms. So with static embeddings
we're not going to do anything too
fancy. Generally the embeddings for each
individual word are going to be combined
in some way. And there's a few different
ways of actually doing that. You may do
just a simple averaging approach or
taking the arithmetic mean of all of the
word vectors giving equal weight to each
one of those words. But there's also a
couple different approaches of applying
in different weighted averaging
techniques like term frequency, inverse
document frequency, and smooth inverse
frequency are essentially going to look
at the frequency of words and give less
of an influence to common words and
emphasize more distinctive terms. which
for an example sentence of something
like I have no interest in hearing about
the rising interest rate of the bank, we
would give less of an importance to
things like of the or about the and more
emphasis on things like interest or bank
or no. But with that, let's actually
take a look at word tovec in action. So
I can import word tovec using the static
vectors package which is a useful
maintained package for working with
static embedding models. Then we can go
down the line and see which if you've
looked at any major content around
embedding models, you'll probably see
the example and the common example that
I'll be doing. But we can do something
like get the embedding for the word
king. And so you'll see that king here
has now become a large array of numbers.
And each one of these numbers is going
to represent a learned dimension about
the word king. These dimensions can be
thought of similar to how you and I
might understand dimensions like we live
in a three-dimensional world. But
thoughts and ideas and things like the
word king have a lot of different
dimensions of understanding to them. In
our case here, we've captured 300
dimensions of the word king in this
vector. And these dimensions can also be
thought of almost geometrically as well
as vector representations are considered
highdimension representations of these
things or ideas. But the intuitive and
easy approach here is to think that each
one of these dimensions kind of
encapsulates a little bit of the nuances
of the idea of the word king. So we can
see that getting the vector for man,
woman and queen respectively gives us
some different 300 dimension vector
representations. Now this might be a
little bit difficult to wrap your head
around as we literally can only imagine
in upwards of three dimensions. But what
we can do is actually look at how these
numbers and dimensions can be used. And
the the biggest approach and most common
one especially for a lot of AI related
pipelines today are going to be doing
some form of semantic similarity or
based on the semantic dense vector
representations that we have output per
each one of these different sequences or
individual words. We can actually
directly and mathematically compare them
together. You can think of this
literally and very similarly to how you
might actually calculate the distance
between two points on a xy line except
in this case we're not looking at two
dimensions. We're looking at the
distance between these points in 300
dimensions. So a little bit more
difficult to wrap your head around. But
if you want to think about it
geometrically that's kind of what's
going on. A very popular thing to do is
actually use cosine similarity which is
more going to compare the actual angles
between two points as they relate to the
center. So what we can do is pop in
these vectors together and calculate the
cosine similarity between them. So we'll
see that from our example queen and king
are about 65% similar. Man and woman are
about 76% similar. King and man are
calculated to be about 22% similar.
Queen and woman at 31, but then king and
woman are going to be a little less
similar and queen and man are going to
be a little less similar. So, you can
see how it's kind of picked up on these
different ideas and are able to kind of
map them back and put the similarity
together based on kind of how they've
been constructed socially and culturally
within human language. Now, one of the
more interesting things about vector
arithmetic is that because we have
representations of words and numbers, we
can start to do some pretty interesting
things. So, I put together a quick
visualization in three dimensions. So,
we're actually going to be reducing the
dimensionality of these words into three
so that we can visualize it in the
highest amount of dimensions that we
understand. Now, we're going to show the
example of taking the vector number of
king, subtracting out the vector number
of man, and adding in the vector number
of woman and see where it lines up.
Spoiler alert. So, looking at this 3D
chart here, we can see some pretty
interesting things. If we look just at
our original point of king here, we can
see that it's pretty close to prince.
And so, those things that are close
together mean that they tend to be
semantically related or semantically
similar. So we see things like father
and son be very close together. Mother
and daughter, woman and girl, boy and
man. And then going back to our example,
we have king here. And subtracting out
the vector for man from king puts a
point over here. But then interestingly
enough, if we take that point and then
add in the vector for woman, we get a
point here. And what is right close by
to queen? That is king minus man plus
woman. But now that we have an
understanding of static embedding models
and how they work and how they're almost
like lookup tables that then get pulled
together to create one final encoded
representation. One of the biggest
issues that you might see is that each
one of the individual learned embeddings
for each of the words are of course
static which means that they suffer from
this cool word polysmy or the
coexistence of many possible meanings
for a word or phrase. What we just went
over a little bit ago showing these
different static versus contextual
embeddings and transformer-based
embedding model diagrams is that things
like I went to the bank, the river bank
was muddy and bank of America that word
and understanding for bank is going is
quite different across all three of
these sentences. But the vector for bank
from a static embedding model is going
to be the same when ran through the
model. That is where things like the
transformer models and attention-based
models actually shine because they're
able to use their attention mechanism to
actually on the fly change the meaning
and representation of a word based on
the context around it. We can visualize
this real quick by looking at the two
sentences. I went to the bank to
withdraw some money and we all swam down
to the muddy riverbank using one of the
models Bertbased uncased which is just
one of the base models that is uncased
meaning that everything is going to be
just in flat lowercase from Google. And
so running this through the BERT model
what we're going to do is actually
visualize the attention mechanism here
within our embeddings. We can see that
within the attention mechanism that the
word bank is being very much so
correlated and influenced by this word
here withdraw. That is of course going
to be in the first sentence. And then in
the second sentence we can see that bank
here is being heavily influenced by
swam. And so that's why the attention
mechanism is able to do these very
nuanced contextual embeddings because it
looks at all of the influence of the
other words in the sentence here to
actually determine its final
representation and understanding of a
word. And we can see that this is backed
up because the similarity between both
banks when we do the cosign similarity
is only going to be 29%. But if we
actually run a different sentence in
like the bank manager approved my loan
for the application and take out the
encoding of this bank, it is going to be
81 or 81% similar to the original
finance related bank word. Enough talk
about transformer-based encodings. We're
here to talk about static models. So, as
I mentioned earlier, while
transformer-based embedding models do
have that impressive contextual
performance, they come with the major
downside of requiring magnitudes more
compute to actually do these
calculations. This is where it is
interesting to actually revisit static
embeddings. And while it's unlikely to
be able to push the higher end of
transformer-based approaches with static
embeddings, using some modern
techniques, we can train a lot better
models. And this was revisited in a
major way by Mr. Tom Arson here who
applied some modern techniques and data
to create a static embedding model that
performed above the BM25 baseline and
almost close to some of the performance
of things like all mini LML6V2. And of
course, the biggest thing here is that
all of this is able to be performed with
incredible speeds of being able to do
almost a 100,000 queries per second.
Now, on top of just having more modern
data sets, the biggest innovation is
actually using contrastive learning.
This is something that we've seen
generally used with aligning multimodal
representations with things like
contrastive language image pre-training
models or clip models that are able to
represent both text and images together
in one space. And this is also kind of
what's powered the interchangeability
and understanding of things like audio,
video, and image understanding in
language models. What we mean by this is
that essentially the learning method is
that the embedding model is going to
calculate the similarities between pairs
or more of text sequences and the inputs
are then going to pass through the model
be encoded into embeddings. We are going
to contrast these examples and their
similarities together and over time
we'll try to position more similar
things together while pushing away
unrelated inputs. This is a little bit
easier to understand when looking at a
data example. If you look at the
original training code, which is in this
blog, which I'll of course have linked
down in the description below, Tom is
using multiple negatives ranking loss,
which essentially is going to include
one anchor sample, one positive sample,
and then multiple negative samples. So
given the input of this anchor as well
as the positive and all of the negatives
input into the model, we are going to
nudge the model towards better
positioning the anchor and the positive
document together while pushing away the
representation in this highdimension
space of these negatives here. The
interesting part here is that the harder
it is to determine between the positives
or the negatives can actually increase
the robustness of the model trained. So
using techniques like hard negative
mining or things like that to provide
very similar yet unrelated examples of
the negatives is a great technique to be
able to do this learning more
effectively. So Tom and the team applied
this with some modern data sets to train
a fully new static embedding model as
well as using some matrioska
representation learning which I've
implemented a few times in some of my
other videos of fine-tuning sentence
embedding models. But what we can do is
go ahead and load it and give it a shot.
So we can run this right on CPU because
it is low parameter account and doesn't
take a lot of effort. And let's go ahead
and compare these sentences. It is known
for its dry red chili powder. It is
popular for dried red chili powder. And
these monsters will move in large
groups. Our expectation is of course
that these two sentences are going to be
similar. And this third will be much
more different than the other two. And
that we can pretty much see. So looking
at this first sentence here, we can see
that it is perfectly similar to itself,
very similar to the second, and then not
quite similar at all to this last one.
But the most impressive thing to
actually take away from this example
that Tom's given us here is that we're
able to push the performance of
embeddings for common tasks like things
like similarity or retrieval above
classic ranking algorithms like BM25 as
a baseline. And we're even getting close
to the performance of things like Almin
Mini LM which in the given evaluations
was just six percentage points behind
Alin LM coming out to 05032
versus.5623 respectively. And all on top
of this, this allows for upwards of
107,000 sentences per second to be
computed on CPU from Tom's
experimentation. Well, in similar
environments, all mini LM can only run
about
1,739 per second. So, increases of up to
62 times speed. Something like this can
be incredibly beneficial for large scale
production settings where a small
accuracy trade-off may be worthwhile.
And also, additional innovations in
static embedding models have been proven
to show that we can push this a little
step forward. So experimenting and
trying things out like this yourself
could lead to some innovative
breakthroughs. I gave this a shot by
just pretty much recreating the training
environment, but this time using modern
burp bases tokenizer instead of burp
base on case like the original. And I
did manage to put together a quick
static embedding model that is going to
be linked down below here. But I was
only able to push this up to
about4791 on the nano bear normalized
discount and cumulative gains at 10
metric which is a common metric for
information retrieval. So I'll be
linking to this article. It's certainly
worth the read. It goes super in-depth
into exactly how this was trained with
code examples as well. So big shout out
to Tom and the team for putting together
this work and open sourcing it quite
nicely. Certainly worth a read. I'll
have it linked in the description below.
But the second topic of the day which
we'll cover briefly at the end here is
actually the embedding model
distillation process where rather than
relying on actually training a full
model from the start, what if we
actually took an existing transformer
contextualbased model and converted it
into a static embedding model? Well,
that's exactly what the aptly named
model 2 vec package does. Well, there is
another blog post that I'll have linked
in the description below for you to
check out. The high-level overview of
how this works is that essentially we're
going to take an existing
transformer-based embedding model, run
every single token in the model's
vocabulary through the model, and then
store those embeddings alongside the
vocabulary. We then go through an
optional dimensionality reduction step.
So we can change it from whatever amount
of dimensions that our original output
is and truncate that into a smaller one
and then also weight each embedding
based on some power rules. This is a
super interesting way of actually
approaching that because essentially
it's going to bootstrap static
embeddings from transformer models by
creating that lookup table of vector
representations directly. It then also
applies the dimensionality reduction and
waiting tokens appropriately without
kind of requiring any sort of extensive
training that we might have seen in some
of our examples before. So just to
quickly go over these three steps, run
every token in the model's vocabulary
through the model and store the
embedding is pretty straightforward. So
I won't go into that one. But reducing
the dimensionality of the output
embedding is going to rely on something
called principal component analysis,
dimensionality reduction or PCA for
short. PCA is a way of taking
highdimensional data and mapping it down
to of course well lower dimensions here
and is what we use to actually take our
300 dimension representation and change
it into three dimensions for our
visualization that we showed earlier
with the king, woman, queen example.
Without getting too much into the math,
the intuitive way of understanding this
is that we're attempting to map the
highdimensional data to lower
dimensional space while maintaining the
geometric distribution of the data as
best as possible. So this means that we
can take large embeddings and
essentially convert them into smaller
embeddings with a minimal loss in the
actual semantic meanings of these
embeddings and their relationships to
each other. This has a few different
benefits in the entire process here. We
can not only store more efficient and
smaller vector representations in total
in our actual lookup table here, but
doing this reduction can help normalize
and actually dn noiseise the data from
any sort of highdimension model specific
information that was learned over the
course of the transformer model
training. So we can reduce any redundant
learnings and also assist in
generalizing our static embedding model
a little bit more. So while we do lose
the specificity of the transformer-based
embedding, this will help make the token
specific embeddings more applicable to
wider scenarios in this static embedding
model. And then handinhand with this is
the third step which is weighting each
of these embeddings. So what I put down
here is that when you really consider
that a static embedding of a sequence,
document or sentence will simply be that
pulled average or some sort of weighted
frequency of the individual token level
embeddings. It is important to add in
some form of individual waiting. This
waiting actually happens pretty much
automatically when we use
attention-based models because we relate
words and their meanings more
specifically to the semantically rich
words that are contextually around them.
So without the luxury of attention, we
essentially are going to use a
simplified version of smooth inverse
frequency based on something called
ZIP's law, which states that when a list
of measured values is sorted in
decreasing order, the value of the nth
entry is often approximately inversely
proportional to n. Or in other words, it
is usually found that the most common
word occurs approximately twice as often
as the next common one, three times as
often as the third most common and so
on. And the thing that we can really
take advantage of is that most
vocabularies for these models are
already frequency ordered lists. So we
can assume that this holds true and
effectively downweight frequent words
and upweight more rare words provided
the list here. So the model tove vec
algorithm applies this three-step
process using a given transformer
embedding model and an optional
vocabulary to pretty much quickly build
the static embedding models based on the
inputs. So let's try it out. We're going
to be using the Beijing Academy of
Artificial Intelligence model
BGEM3 which is a multilingual embedding
model basically because it is about 560
million parameters. So, it's quite a
beefy and capable one and is able of
processing sequences of up to
8,192 tokens down into 1,024 dimension
vector representations. So, what we're
going to do is take this model and
specify it and then we're going to do
the dimensionality reduction of 256.
So just kicking this off, what you're
going to see actually happen is the
model will be loaded if you don't have
it downloaded already and then it's
going to start going through each
individual word and its vocabulary and
storing the embedding that comes out
from the model. So you'll see that my
video's gotten a little bit choppy as my
CPU is under load computing these
embeddings. So, I'll be back in a couple
minutes as this finishes up. So, once
that's gone ahead and finished up, I've
saved it just in a quick folder here.
Then I'll load the regular model as well
as the distilled model onto CPU. And
what we're going to do is use a quick
anchor positive and negative example. So
I have this what is Ddier Ruf best known
for as a photographer as well as a
provided positive here in the second
position and a negative in the third
position here. If we run through the
embeddings and calculate the
similarities for both of the models,
what we can see here is something pretty
interesting. We see from the base model
that our anchor and positive is at a 75%
similarity and our anchor and negative
is at a 35% similarity. And then looking
at our distilled model of the BGE M3, we
see that the anchor and positive is
at.37 and the anchor and negative is at
10. So while our direct computations are
a little bit different, the actual
expected result of having a higher
similarity between the positive and the
anchor versus the positive and the
negative still holds true in this case.
And at the end of it all, we have a
nicely distilled down sentence embedding
model as a static embedding model that
we can use for any sort of downstream
task. So to close off our discussion
here today, my main kind of point is
that while modern-day embedding models
based on transformers can create robust
dynamic embeddings, applying new data
and approaches to old techniques have
found static embedding models working
their way back into the stack. In this,
the latest in research in this area
begins to provide a competitive output
to some of the most used transformer
models, but at a fraction of the
parameters and resources required to run
and up to 400 times faster in
comparison. So, it's a very compelling
and interesting thing to keep your eye
out on or even do some experiments
yourself with if interested. With all
that being said, hope you learned
something interesting today. If you like
the video, like the video. If you have
any questions, leave them in the
comments below. And if you want to see
more like this, consider subscribing. If
you want to support the channel further,
consider leaving a super thanks or
joining a channel membership.