embedding. They are the secret source
behind every smart AI apps you have ever
used. From Google search to chat GPD
memory to the recommendation for you
feeds that somehow knows exactly what
you want. But here's the catch. Most
embedding model are either too big to
run locally or too generic to work for
your data. That's where Google's brand
new embedding Gemma changes the game. At
just 308 million parameter, this tiny
beast can run offline on your laptop or
even on your phone while still beating
model twice its size on the industry
gold standard benchmark benchmarks. And
in this video, I am going to show you
something Google does not teach you in
the docs. How to fine-tune embedding
Gemma on your own data set. So imagine
this, you have got thousands of customer
support chats, research paper or even
your personal notes. Instead of relying
on generic embedding will train Gemma to
understand specific domain language. So
your AI AI app can answer question more
accurately, recommend better context or
even become
private offline search engine for your
file. So stick around because end of the
tutorial you'll not only know how to
fine-tune Gemma but also how to evaluate
your embedding so you don't just guess
that it's working you actually prove it.
All right let's dive in. Now let's start
the training of this model. So we are
going to train this on our custom data
set. For that we'll need to ensure that
we are on running on the GPU server. So
make sure T4 is selected and then
install the dependency that it requires.
So this dependency will take about 1 or
2 minutes. Once this is done, you'll
need to make sure that
the version is correct as I have written
in the URL. So let's clear this out and
let's log into hugging faces. You'll
need to provide the token
and once this is done we can download
the model from Google embedding 300
million parameter model. So this will
ensure uh that the model is downloaded
but you need to do a sign up or uh
agreement acceptance that you need to do
from your site. So that will be done in
hugging face. Once this is done, we'll
need to prepare our data set as a
triplet. So from data set, let's import
load data set and we'll create a custom
function which is triplet. It is going
to take two sentences and one negative
sentence. From this data set, we'll get
two sentences and their similarity
distance.
So since we know that uh similar
sentence will have less distance. So
let's prepare our third sentence from
there randomly where the similarity is
high. So now we'll create a condition
and take our uh negative sentence. From
there we can create a triplet anchor and
positive is going to be the same but
we'll have a far distance embedding as
the negative sentence. So once this is
done uh from data set we are going to uh
uh load this and prepare the dev test
and train triplet. So let's print this
out and see how uh the data set
preparation is being done.
As here you can see the data set for
training has about 1,000 examples
and for dev and test it has 100 200 and
200. It is having anchor positive and
negative. And see one of the examples of
the training set like a plane is taking
off. The positive one is a airplane is
taking off and the negative is a young
wearing a hat. So that makes sense. Now
we need to define the task name which is
SDS. So this task name will be passed to
the model which encodes this query into
embedding and also for uh the documents
uh that we are preparing. So once doing
that you'll need to do the similarity
between the query and your documents.
This similarity will tell how two are
related. So here you see I have written
one food example where breakfast will
should have a higher embedding lower
embedding distance compared to rest of
these two. So let's run it.
As you can see this is doing pretty well
from the base model itself. So let's say
for example if you want to uh uh now
finetune it on your own data set then
you'll have to use the sentence
transform as trainer
and from there uh you'll need to pass
it's a configurable argument and the
loss function is multiple negative
ranking loss that you'll need to pass
your model that prepares your loss and
this is these are the arguments uh we
have to take the prompt with the STS
task for this I'm going to run it for
one epoch and learning rate is very
small and we not going to uh report this
to weights and bias otherwise you can
put there then you'll have to log in
your weights and bias now this is a
custom call back where which at the end
of the training it is going to do the
evaluation call the evaluation function
and will evaluation function is just the
same
query the document that we have run
above here you can see this is going to
run it while doing the during the
evaluation.
So once uh this is done we can start the
training and pass the model arguments
data set loss function and what is going
to be the call back. So let's run it and
see
uh how how it is working. I have already
ran it for now. I'm going to run it. And
you can see your GPU consumption will
start to increase from there.
So let's give it a minute.
Uh it's going to take one about 1
minutes from here. So
uh after the training it is going to
save the model and then you can use it
for uh doing the inference on your
server or you wanted to host this
locally for your use case. This model is
very useful for uh mobile devices and
where applications where the latency is
matter latency matters and resource
constraint devices is going to be very
useful.
So once this training is done you can
use this model and thank you for
following this session. Thank you very
much.